Colored Hearing Improved By SidBrothers _ 3
( CONTINUES GUTTURAL CHANTING )
( MORE VOICES JOIN IN CHANTING )
( BREATH EXHALING )
( CHANTING GROWS LOUDER )
( SCREAMING )
WOMAN : My dearest father ...
I pray that you have not been consumed with worry
in the time that has passed since I was taken .
I write to you in the hope that you will put an end to my suffering
on this wretched island .
My captors inform me that if I am to survive ,
you must travel here alone with the means to purchase my freedom .
That should a man of law be sent in your stead , it would seal my fate .
Father , I grow weary .
" I fear our Lord no longer hears my prayer .
Yet still , I pray for your presence ...
for my savior .
Please bring me home .
Your beloved daughter ...
Jennifer . "
The world thinks you 're dead .
And then , till I found you , I thought the same .
That ransom letter ...
it was addressed to him .
Look at him .
He 's broken .
He lost .
Doesn 't even know you 're here ... let alone that she 's gone .
Whatever ill there is that stands ...
stands between you and him , not your sister .
She needs you , Thomas .
Now more than ever .
And what of the ransom ?
SECRETARY : They won 't be expecting you .
Stay hidden among his flock .
But do not pay the ransom they seek ...
until you see her .
Alive .
These people ...
they 're blasphemers ...
a cult , a disease .
Be careful . Be smart .
Bring her home .
( PANTING )
( EXHALING )
( TRAIN BRAKES SQUEALING )
( TRAIN WHISTLE )
( STEAM HISSING )
( DISTANT CLANGING )
MAN : Have your tickets ready , please .
All printed materials , corrupting images , ornaments , decorations from the mainland
are strictly forbidden .
Clothing ... and heirlooms only .
Welcome , brother .
Welcome , sister .
- May I help you , brother ? - Much thanks , sir .
MAN : Welcome , brother .
Welcome , brother .
Welcome , sister .
MAN : Thank you , sir .
MAN : Welcome , brother .
Welcome , brother .
Welcome , sister .
( WAVES CRASHING )
MAN : Full ahead !
- Brother ... - Sister .
Forgive me , it 's just ...
I don 't recall having seen you at any prayer meetings .
Nor I you .
Some happenstance ?
Quite . Only ...
Only we meet now .
We do .
( GRUNTING )
( GRUNTING CONTINUES )
( FRIGHTENED BLEATING INTENSIFIES )
( SPLASH )
( BLEATING FADING AWAY )
It was as intended .
Only She decides whether to give or take .
We do not intervene .
( ALL
CHANTING ) Amen .
Let me , sir .
( SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
( CHILDREN SHOUTING AND PLAYING )
Welcome to Erisden , sir .
- Should you need anything ... - I don 't need anything , boy .
Ffion .
- Prepare the table . - Aye , Father .
MAN : All new citizens , please line up .
Oh , my !
( LAUGHING )
Open your mouth , please . Put your tongue out .
Okay , thank you .
- Name ? - Elaine Williams .
( WRITING ON PAPER )
- Age ? - Thirty-eight .
- Hello . Let 's look here . - CLERK : Skill or trade ?
- [ ELAINE : Seamstress . - Okay .
- CLERK : Tell of your donation . - [ ELAINE : I offer my undying devotion ...
Open your mouth and put your tongue out , please .
- [ ELAINE : ... drop of my blood to Our Lady . - CLERK : As we should .
CLERK : Criminal record ?
Vagrancy .
Worry not , Elaine . You 'll want for nothing here .
Please take your receptacle .
Welcome to Erisden , Elaine .
That 's good .
Name ?
Thomas Richardson .
BELL CHIMING )
MAN AND WOMAN : ♫ Broad is the road that leads to death ♫
♫ And thousands walk together there ... ♫
( SINGING CONTINUING )
( HURRIED FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
How long ago did he begin ?
I have no idea .
At least I 'm not the last to arrive . He hates that .
You 've got , uh ... something on your ...
Don 't tell .
♫ ... And makes his own destruction sure ♫
Radicalist !
Conspirator .
Traitor !
Enemy of the King .
Those are the words they attributed to me ...
as they shackled my hands and the hands of my brothers ...
before they imprisoned us on the charge of treason .
Sentenced to death .
But for what ?
My only crime was to dare to dream of a world
in which each waking day we rise equal .
Compassion is no crime .
But my fate was not to be found in death , my friends .
No , no .
Three brothers we became ...
bonded by our escape .
Stowaways , cast into the rough seas .
Oh , the taste of the ocean beating down my throat , I shall never forget .
But ...
nor will I ...
the sweet , sweet sound ...
of her voice ...
as she beckoned us out of the storm .
She ...
the goddess of this island ,
who saved us ...
and who chose my ...
chose my tongue ... through which to speak .
A man who once walked godless ,
she gifted me her wisdom ,
entrusted me that I may enrich ... your minds .
I ask you all ... where is the land which has no call for wars ?
Hmm ?
Arms ? Money ? Nor taxes ?
Well , that land is here .
No tax-gatherer 's bill shall ever threaten our church door !
We , I tell thee , we ...
we are free men .
( WHIMPERING )
( CHILDREN LAUGHING )
GIRL : Come on ! Let 's play !
BOY : Wait for me !
( GASPING )
( DOOR CLOSES )
What 's this ?
He wouldn 't tell us where the money is .
Well , now you 've so broken the man , he can 't tell us ...
even if he wanted to !
- You 've brought the wrong man . - It 's him .
Of course it 's him . He 's the one that gave me this .
It has the mark .
( SINGING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
My brother .
( SINGING ) I have promised you a life of riches without the icy sting of suffering ,
greed , and injustice .
And yet here you are ...
and there you suffer .
- Ssh , ssh .
We have an intruder on our land .
He 's out there ... somewhere . He knows to remain hidden .
We have to find him .
( LIVELY FOLK MUSIC PLAYING )
( LAUGHTER )
( DOOR SLAMMING )
( DOOR SLAMMING CLOSED )
Did you miss me ?
You were only away for two sunsets .
Aye , and two sunrises .
( CHUCKLES )
One day , I promise , we won 't have to hide like this .
We 'll have our own house , with our own name .
We can take this boat and use the wood .
(
CHUCKLES ) You 'll ... .
You 're going to build me a house using this now , are you ?
No , you 're right . It 's a stupid ... stupid idea .
No .
I 'm sorry .
It 's beautiful .
And look , we have enough to make a front door ,
enough to carve the name of our home onto it ,
and we can hang it up in the rafters .
And everyone who knows us , they 'll see ... and they 'll know it 's ours .
No one will ever stop me taking care of you .
I love you , Jeremy .
Ffion , we shouldn 't .
It 's all right .
I 'm with you , Jeremy .
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WAVES GENTLY CRASHING )
( WOOD CREAKING RHYTHMICALLY )
Call to quarters !
Back to your dwellings !
The hour of night is here .
Call to quarters !
( LAUGHTER AND SHOUTING )
( DOOR SLAMMING )
Ah .
Sorry .
( FOOTSTEPS )
Shh .
It 's okay .
( GASPING )
( KEY TURNING )
( COUGHS )
( KNOCKING )
Who is it ?
JEREMY : It 's , um ... It 's me , sir .
What is it ?
Time for work .
( HAMMERING )
( SAWING )
Five more , and she 'll do !
Five more !
What is it ?
Uh , sir , last night , I 'd like to know why you ... What ...
Why was I outside ?
I was having a cigarette .
Why were you ?
Such distrust .
And I was of a mind I could put my faith in you .
Sorry , sir . I beg your forgiveness .
I mean no insult or quarrel , I just ...
I have limited thought , and ...
Sorry .
No , I apologize , Jeremy .
Forgive my lack of grace .
I will gladly forgive you , sir ...
so long as you 'll be so good as to help me ?
With what ?
You dragged this here by yourself ?
Not I. A man .
Malcolm , he says the man wanted to bring death here . Says he was a spy .
He tried to leave , but the sea took him .
She protected us .
Did she ?
Do many seek to leave the island ?
Just the blasphemers .
Are they granted safe passage ?
Why do you ask , sir ? You 've been here but a day .
I can trust you , can 't I , Jeremy ?
Of course , sir . What bothers you ?
- Sir , I must go now . - No , you don 't !
You know her . Yes , you do , I can see that you do .
For Christ 's sake , be a man , not a child .
- I don 't know of what you speak . - You 're lying !
Please , I should go . I should .
Look her in the eye and lie to me again . You know her .
Say it .
I knew her .
A month ago , she was on our boat .
Frank said we had no choice .
The crops are failing , the animals have stopped breeding .
We have no means to smuggle food in from the mainland .
He said her father was rich ,
but we only wanted his money so we wouldn 't starve .
But it never came .
( MUFFLED WHIMPERING )
( SCREAMING )
Why didn 't you help her ?
Look at me , Mr. Richardson .
If they thought I had any part , if they caught her in my charge ...
They ? Who 's they ?
Prophet Malcolm 's guards . Please , sir , I beg of you .
If you are in possession of the ransom they seek , do not pay it .
You , boy , are in my charge .
If you wish to keep your affair with that girl in the shadows ,
you will serve me during my time on this land ,
and hold fast the purpose of my being here . Do you understand ?
Good .
MALCOLM : Hold her down , for fuck 's sake !
Jesus , it 's turned .
Pull .
( GRUNTING )
( FEEBLE BLEATING )
We cannot go on like this .
( PANTING )
She will gift us another pure harvest .
Have faith .
( BELL CLANGING )
All new arrivals , please make your way to the church !
Ffion ?
What is it ?
Tell me .
You 're ... you 're knowledgeable .
You would know if I ...
if I should be with child .
Well , first , you and Jeremy would have to ...
Frequently ... For many moons .
Andrea , I know what we do is a sin .
Do you love him ?
With all my heart .
Then do not judge yourself as sinners .
When was it you last bled ?
The winter months .
That may already be your answer .
But there are ways to see ...
To know ...
Sorry .
All new arrivals are requested at the church .
As the leader of this community ,
it seems I have failed to make clear the rules ...
that bind us .
Under no circumstances ...
are any members of this village , new or old ,
permitted to venture out after the ringing of the night bell .
But last night ... ( CHUCKLES )
one of you ...
broke that rule .
Kneel ... if you would be so kind .
Book of Therese ,
verse seven , chapter 12 .
" For I shall profit not ...
I will seek not ... "
" ... the gold of my brother ,
for he hath not more than I , nor I than him .
For my life ... "
Shh , shh .
" For my life is not defined by consumption ,
wealth , and material goods .
It is an echo of my neighbor and of my neighbor 's neighbor .
We , the people of ... "
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
MAN : " We , the people of Erisden ,
stand bonded in our unity ,
stand united through equality ,
for we shall suffer not ,
shall want not . "
Well ?
For King and country !
( BOTH GRUNTING )
Agh !
( PANTING )
This heathen land ...
will ... burn !
[ knife clanging on floor ]
( PANTING )
( GROANING )
Agh !
Treat the man ! Do it !
He was from the mainland . An assassin . His knife has the King 's markings .
Did you bring anyone at all that you weren 't supposed to ?
( MOANING )
If the knife of that bastard cut just one of us ,
we all bleed together .
If your blood has been shed in my name , I shed mine for you .
- Father !
I 'm indebted to you , brother .
Your act of bravery shall not go unrewarded .
You have my word .
Today the King sends spies . How long before he sends ships ?
I want spotters stationed along the coastline .
Strengthen our defense .
- Load the carriages , arm the barricade . - Aye !
- Travel to the north point . - To the north point !
( GROANING )
( SCREAMING )
We 're not done here yet .
The intruder still walks , and we have a ransom to find .
All right , collect the girl .
If he insists on remaining hidden , we 'll show him the consequences .
( HORSE TROTTING AND NEIGHING )
Afraid I spilt a little .
How dare you !
How long did this collection take ?
Trinkets like these are not easily acquired .
My uncle .
My mother 's kin .
He 's a doctor .
Is that your mother ?
Yes .
She died giving birth to me .
I 'm sorry .
My uncle says I remind him of her .
Says it gives him peace to know she lives through me .
All my life , he 's been the only one who could look at me ,
see her , and still smile .
My father ...
sometimes I can just see it his eyes .
A resentment .
Do you resent him ?
- Sir ? - Your father , for bringing you here .
- Mr. Richardson ... - Don 't misunderstand me .
I 'm glad that he did , but ...
You strike me as somebody with more to give this world
than merely being the daughter of a prophet .
- Do you resent yours ? - Oh , every day .
A few drops of these should see you through the night .
I 'll come by tomorrow to change your bandages .
Thank you , Miss Howe .
( BELL CLANGING )
MAN : Call to quarters !
MALCOLM : People of Erisden !
Hear me !
The woman you see before you ...
has broken the laws of our land !
She is an agent of a dying god ...
and a weak King .
She 's come here to corrupt ...
and destroy our community !
But ...
there is another .
Her kin is here also .
Co-conspirator !
I call to him now !
Make yourself known .
Make good ... on the debt ...
that she owes ...
and forgiveness shall be hers .
Stay in the shadows ...
and it be the Heathen 's Stand that awaits ye both !
Very well .
( WHIMPERING )
No ! No !
Don 't ! No !
No !
No , no !
( SCREAMING )
Stop !
Please , no !
( SCREAMING )
MALCOLM : The sands of time are sinking !
Her life is in your hands !
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( CREAK )
( LAUGHING )
( BOYS AND GIRLS LAUGHING )
( YELLS )
Let them play .
( BOYS RESUME LAUGHING )
- You good ? - Aye .
We don 't have the resources for this , Malcolm .
These festivities will decimate our livestock .
Celebrating our way into starvation .
Tonight , while they celebrate ...
we 'll search their rooms .
If he 's here , we 'll know it .
First , we find the money , then we 'll ...
Well , we 'll deal with them both . Trust me , this ends tonight .
Andrea ?
Off from her , now !
Can we at least afford this woman her dignity ?
( WHIMPERING )
Slowly .
Slowly , or your body will reject it .
Thank you .
I 'll see to it that no one harms you . I promise .
Just hold strong .
( HAMMERING )
Come on !
Get up !
Go !
Be ready .
( LAUGHING )
( FIDDLE AND DRUM MUSIC PLAYING )
( DOOR OPENING )
Agh .
( LAUGHING )
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING AWAY )
( FIDDLE AND DRUM MUSIC )
Good evening .
( LAUGHTER )
Well , hello .
What 's all this ?
There 's more to life than harvest and prayer , Mr. Richardson .
It 's called " fun " . You should try it .
- Thomas . - Are you going to ask me to dance ?
( CHUCKLES ) It would be an honor , my lady , but ...
do you think the prophet will permit ?
I 'm not sure my father would be persuaded .
I sincerely doubt he 'd be happy with hands such as these ...
on the hips of his good little girl .
These are far from scholarly hands , Mr. Richardson .
Thomas .
And I never proclaimed to be as such .
Your eyes ...
they 've seen things .
Who are you ?
Will you excuse me , Andrea ?
Wait .
Come on .
( MUSIC ENDS )
( APPLAUSE )
- I found these . - You 've done well . Let 's go .
( MUSIC RESUMES )
( CLANG )
( CLING )
- Are you going ... - ( CLING )
We 're wasting our time here , Quinn .
Every room , Malcolm .
Let 's move on !
What is it ?
It 's the house .
Frank ! Frank !
The house !
- Close it after . Don 't seal it . - Yes , sir .
Jeremy ... if you meet any trouble ...
use this .
No matter who it is .
Thank you .
( FOOTSTEPS )
Agh !
Get !
( WHIMPERING )
Go on , go !
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING AWAY )
Frank !
Down here .
He 's inside .
Okay , Frank , take my hunting rifle , get down there and flush him out .
Quinn , stand guard should he return .
Should be me down there .
I want him a prisoner in possession of answers , not a corpse .
Frank .
Don 't hesitate .
You see him , you shoot him .
( DRIPPING )
( HORSE WHINNYING )
( FOOTSTEPS )
Wait , don 't shoot ! It 's me !
Jesus Christ , man !
( BREATHING )
( RETCHING )
Agh !
Ah !
( GASPING )
( SHRINKING )
( PANTING )
( LOUD WAILING )
( EERIE SHOUTING AND SCREAMING )
( SHRINKING )
( SILENCE )
( DRIPPING )
What ...
( PANTING )
( GASPING )
You showed yourself .
To him .
Why ?
He 's not to be trusted .
He won 't worship you ...
as I.
( GROANING )
Ah .
( MOANING )
No more shall you poison our crop .
I swear you shall starve ,
lest you give us pure harvest !
( GASPING )
( MOANING )
( WHIMPERING )
( MUFFLED PROTESTS )
( CRYING )
WOMAN : No ! No !
No !
( SCREAMING )
( MOANING )
You found it .
What is this ?
You wouldn 't believe me .
Here .
Change into these .
What happened to you ?
My faith .
I once held fast a belief in the divine .
Like you , I ...
knelt before a deity .
Armed with the book of Jesus Christ , I ...
led my parish into the heart of Peking .
And we showed them the glory and the love of God himself ...
and then they showed us the Devil .
( GROANING )
( LOUD EXPLOSION )
( HORSE GALLOPING )
MAN : No !
( EXPLOSION )
( SCREAMING )
- ( GUNSHOT ) - (
SCREAMING )
( SHOUTING )
Agh !
( PANTING )
Blessed be , my Father , I beg of You , hear my prayer !
Agh !
As Your faithful servant , in this hour of need ,
I pray for Your divine intervention !
Agh !
( SCREAMING )
( SHOUTING )
Please ! Show Yourself !
( SCREAMING )
( CLOTH RIPPING )
Agh !
The promise of the Divine is but an illusion .
Nothing in this world is pure ...
except for Jennifer ...
my sister .
Always in my heart .
She did not abandon me then ...
and I will not abandon her now .
As for God ,
he left me , left all of us to suffer .
But you survived .
Only my body , and barely that .
God is pain ...
is ... suffering ...
- is betrayal . - Is forgiveness .
Tsk .
Thomas , let me help you .
Says the daughter of the man who wants me dead .
No . Not I , and not my father .
Child , you must be blind to think otherwise .
He may be many things , Mr. Richardson , but he 's not a murderer .
- He wouldn 't . - Oh , he would .
And he has .
" Beware of false prophets which come to you in sheep 's clothing ,
but inwardly they are ravening wolves . "
Andrea , you know it to be true .
My sister ...
is no traitor .
No spy .
She didn 't come here .
She was taken .
( WAVES CRASHING )
Frank ?
She provided for us ...
once .
Enough of your superstition .
Where are we ?
Worry not . They won 't know to look for you here .
It 's toxic .
All the crops have become riddled with impurities .
Look .
All this land ...
it 's scorched earth that we live upon .
And yet , somehow , it grows .
Why now ?
I don 't know .
Perhaps her strength is fading .
Or something has angered her .
Pregnant ?
Ffion , Frank wants I should travel with him today to the mainland .
Then I 'll be at shore to greet you at sunrise .
He wants I should stay there .
Jeremy ...
And I want only should you be there by my side ...
as my wife .
( CHUCKLES )
Well , you know yourself ,
your father would never allow it . Me , you ...
us ...
our child .
We could be together ...
any time of any day .
- Free . - To love each other .
Wait .
Wait right here . I have something ... for us .
( GASPING )
Father ?
Father , please . I can explain .
Please ! I was going to tell you . Please ...
Agh !
( SOBBING )
Tell me now !
What suspicions have ye confirmed ?
Father , no !
No !
Inform me , child ! Lest I see what ye hide !
It 's mine to keep !
Where you going , Frank ?
The boy and me are leaving .
Frank ...
Sorry , Malcolm .
I can 't be part of this anymore . I won 't .
This community needs you .
I need you .
You need my boat .
I was happy following you
when this was all about the word of your heart .
Come on , Frank . This ...
this is our island .
We built this ...
with our own hands . You , me ... Quinn .
It 's our paradise .
No . It 's our hell , and I 'm dragging the boy down with me .
And you , your Andrea .
No , no .
No , no , you 're wrong , Frank .
We have homes here . We have families .
- We have faith . - ( SINGING ) Oh , faith ...
We have a god in chains poisoning us from the inside out .
We have an innocent man 's blood on our hands .
We have a kidnapped girl , held for ransom .
I 'll go to my grave washing the blood of that wee soul from my hands .
This place , this community , it 's broken .
Then we 'll fix it !
Together .
It 's finished .
You know it in your heart .
Whose is it ?
Who put that inside you ?
Please ...
Father , do not see it for the judgment of his actions .
Oh , no . No , no , no .
Pray no .
- Not him . - He followed only what I asked .
This is a harlot 's tongue !
Them be a whore 's lips that move before me !
Look into my eyes ,
and see the daughter that stands frightened and in need of a father 's love !
You have no idea what monstrosity grows inside you !
This is an abomination !
- A bastard mongoloid breed ! - No !
To be born in lumps of twisted flesh no mother would ever call her own .
- No ! - Yes ... child .
I 've seen it .
That thing ...
It will kill you .
( SOBBING )
I won 't stand for it .
Here .
No ! No !
No ! Stop !
Ffion ?
QUINN : You did this .
You put your seed ...
inside my beautiful angel .
I had no choice .
My Ffion .
My daughter !
And you ...
took her from me .
QUINN : Agh !
Agh !
Agh ! Agh !
( SCREAMING )
Help !
Help ! Help !
Somebody help !
He killed her !
He killed my girl !
No ...
No , I didn 't .
Murderer !
Don 't let him escape !
After him !
GUARD : This way !
Prepare the Heathen 's Stand !
By order of purification !
MAN : But , sir , only Prophet Malcolm ...
Malcolm is not the divine ruler of this land !
Now , follow my orders .
Or I swear ...
by the blood of my kin ...
ye shall face the same fate .
Now !
Sound the alarm .
( BELL CLANGING )
What 's happening ?
( PANTING )
Andrea !
Jeremy ! Jeremy !
Please , help me . I didn 't hurt her . I swear I didn 't touch her !
What are you talking about ? What 's happened ?
Jeremy , where is Ffion ?
I didn 't do it ! It was him . He ripped our child from her !
( BLOWS )
- Jeremy ! - Get back !
The boy killed her . He needs to be purified .
- No ! - Pick him up !
No !
Jeremy !
Listen to his words !
Listen !
Jeremy ! Agh !
Please !
No ! Stop , please !
( SCREAMING )
GUARD : Lift !
You monster !
Restrain him !
You know that boy would never hurt Ffion .
He has nothing but love in his heart for her .
Is this the love of which you speak ?
( SCREAMING )
I , a father ...
robbed of kin ,
even in this ,
a moment of unforgiving grief ,
am merciful .
( WHIMPERING )
Am I not ?
- How could you ? How could you ? - He shall be cleansed ...
Please !
... according to the edict of this land .
ANDREA : Don 't let this happen ! Please , don 't let this happen !
ANDREA : Oh , please ! Please !
Let us begin .
( GASPING )
I 've wanted this .
( SCREAMING )
( GROANING )
Agh ...
I grant unto thee ...
this symbol of purity .
Let it guide you .
( SOBBING )
Pray for him .
MALCOLM : Quinn ?
Jeremy ?
My boy !
( SOBBING ) My boy !
QUINN : Take him .
Why ?
Tragedy befalls us both , my friend .
Your boy took my Ffion .
No , not my boy !
- What have you done ? - I have brought justice .
Give me my boy !
No .
No , you have no right .
- I am still the leader of this land ! - Not anymore !
This man be a false prophet !
He is weak .
We 've suffered for it .
I have faltered , aye .
And I am repentant .
We can rebuild anew .
Ask yourselves ...
who will see us through these dark days ?
Who will see to it that this land sustains us ?
Who ... will drive a spear
through the hearts of those that oppose our god ?
- But at what cost ? - Whatever it takes .
Prove yourself .
This man ... is the enemy we have long sought .
He seeks to destroy ...
our way of life .
We demand justice !
Do we not ?
Before the eyes of your child ...
and all that doubt you ...
take this man 's life .
Father , don 't .
Hush , child .
Lift him .
Father , do not mistake this man as thy enemy .
Trust me , child , I do not mistake him .
- I know who this man really is . - As do I of you !
Please be not who I fear you have become .
( LOUD GUNSHOT )
What are you doing , Frank ?
Stay back ! This has to end .
- Frank ? Wait ! - She has to die .
ANDREA : Father !
Thomas , stop it . Please ! Please ...
QUINN : This way !
( GUNSHOT )
Burn it all down .
Enough !
Go .
- Take your hand off my gun , Malcolm . - It 's over , Quinn . Look at him .
- Let go ! - I said look at him !
Quinn ..
( CREATURE GROANING )
Agh !
( THUD )
( MOANING )
- Jen . - (
WHIMPERING )
Ssh . It 's Thomas .
It 's Tom , it 's Tom . Ssh .
- (
WHIMPERING ) - Ssh . It 's Tom .
I 'm going to get you out , I 'll get you out .
I 'll get you out .
Ssh . I 've got you .
Ssh , ssh .
( WHIMPERING )
Jennifer ! Jennifer ! Jennifer !
- Thomas ! - Ssh , ssh .
- Ssh , ssh .
Let me see you . Let me see you .
( SOBBING )
- I can 't . - I know . I know . Ssh .
I am going to get you out of here .
Ssh .
Father ... They told me you were dead .
Well , to him , I was .
But I 'm here now ...
for you .
( GASPS )
( ROARING AND SCREAMS )
( SILENCE )
ANDREA : Upon bended knee , I call upon Thee .
Please , Lord ...
protect me in my hour of need .
And watch over my father .
Guide me as I seek solace ...
from the hurt of those who wish to inflict it .
I beg of You ...
hear my prayer .
Aaaagghh !
Aagh !
Aagh ...
Aaagghh ...
Aaaggh !
Agh !
Aaaagghh !
Agghh ...
Aagghh !
Aaagghh !
Agh !
Aaagghh ...
Aagh ...
Aa-aagghh ...
Aagghh ...
Aagh ...
Aaagghhh !
Aa-aagh !
Aaagghh !
Aagh !
(
CREATURE
GROWLING )
Agh !
( CREATURE ROARING )
Oh , how I 've waited for you , my son .
How dare you !
My father will see to it that you never ...
Your father can 't help you no more , child .
I saw to it .
No .
QUINN : Years ...
I 've sat and watched ...
as those ingrates gave thanks to your father .
False prophet ...
hiding behind a false god !
I should have had that praise !
Should have been me they thanked !
After all , it was I that imprisoned her .
I , who discovered what she could do for us .
( SCREAMING )
( SHRINKING )
Hold her legs down !
( SOBBING )
Set me free , my child .
Forgive me .
( SHRINKING )
QUINN : Your father was right about her .
You put a god between your enemy and the people ,
put the word of the Almighty between the crosshairs of their muskets ,
you 'll see !
The people won 't falter ... not one bit !
Faith ...
binds you .
God ...
slave ...
mine !
But she 's no god .
She 's just a machine .
You feed her ...
and she ...
delivers .
Malcolm ...
he was soft .
When the blood of the animals stopped working ...
he tried to feed her himself .
Hm ?
He fell victim ... to faith .
He would have let us all starve .
Instead of doing what needed to be done .
Instead of feeding her what she needed to be fed .
Look above you .
That will be your sun ...
your cloud ...
your moon ...
your only way of knowing that a day has passed .
And many will .
For I will save this village .
You ...
will avail your bodies to me .
And when it is ripened ...
I will feed her ...
the flesh of your womb .
And every year ...
we shall celebrate .
MAN : Fire !
Fire !
( SHOUTING )
( SCREAMING AND SHOUTING )
MAN : Brothers !
Sisters !
Your Bibles !
Your texts !
We must leave this island now !
Quinn ! Where 's Quinn ?
He took her ! He took Andrea !
- Where ? - The church !
- Don 't let the boat leave without her . - May God be with you , Mr. Richardson .
And also with you .
Unchain us !
Consider it a mercy .
Agh !
Aaagh !
No ! No !
Aaagghhh ... .
Aaaghh ... !
( SOBBING )
( PANTING )
The boat 's waiting for you .
For all of us .
We have to go .
No ! Thomas !
- Go ! Leave me ... - No !
- You 'll never make it . - No ! I can 't leave you .
You have to . Look at me , Jen .
- Please ... - I can 't feel my legs .
JENNIFER : I don 't want to lose you again .
THOMAS : You never did , and you never will .
Don 't do this ...
Not now !
This world ... has taken so much from me .
But in all my pain , even in my darkest days ,
I swore ... I swore it would never take you .
Now go , get on that boat ,
live , and be the light that guides me to eternity .
Always in my heart .
And you ... And you in mine .
Pray for me .
Come , children ! Quickly !
Join the boat !
We leave now !
( HIGH-PITCHED SHRINKING )
( GENTLE RUSTLING )
( BREATHING DEEPLY )
( WHIMPERS )
♫ Mother of mine ♫
♫ You gave to me ♫
♫ All of my life ♫
♫ To do as I please ♫
♫ I owe everything ♫
♫ I have to you ♫
♫ Mother , sweet Mother ♫
♫ Of mine ♫
♫ Mother of mine ♫
♫ When I was young ♫
♫ You showed me the right way ♫
♫ Things had to be done ♫
♫ Without your love ♫
♫ Where would I be ? ♫
♫ Mother , sweet Mother ♫
♫ Of mine ♫
♫ Mother , you gave me ♫
♫ Happiness ♫
♫ Much more than words ♫
♫ Can say ♫
♫ I pray the Lord ♫
♫ That he may bless you ♫
♫ Every night ♫
♫ And every day ♫
♫ Mother of mine ♫
♫ Now I have grown ♫
♫ And I can walk straight ♫
♫ All on my own ♫
♫ I 'd like to give you ♫
♫ What you gave to me ♫
♫ Mother , sweet Mother ♫
♫ Of mine ♫
♫ Mother , you gave me ♫
♫ Happiness ♫
♫ Much more than words ♫
♫ Can say ♫
♫ I pray the Lord ♫
♫ That he may bless you ♫
♫ Every night ♫
♫ And every day ♫
♫ Mother of mine ♫
♫ Now I am grown ♫
♫ And I can walk straight ♫
♫ All on my own ♫
♫ I 'd like to give you ♫
♫ What you gave to me ♫
♫ Mother , sweet Mother ♫
♫ Of mine ♫
♫ Of mine ... ♫
Colored Hearing Improved By SidBrothers _ 3